They say this world has a lot of evil things ,
yet , it is beautiful at the same time .
I don 't know if they are right ...
but I 'm about to get to know this world all over again .
Wong Kar Mun , I 'm giving you a local anesthetic now .
The operation will take about two hours . Are you ready ?
Who 's that ?
Quiet ! Do you want to alarm all the nurses ?
I 'm in the bed next to yours .
I heard that you 've just gone through an eye operation .
I 've had many operations here .
Everyone here is a good friend of mine .
How old are you ? Why did you need so many operations ?
Eleven years old . I should be in junior high by now ,
but Mum said , there 's an extra black lump in my brain ,
which affects my nervous system .
Which means I can simply pass out at any given moment .
I need open surgery to remove the lump ,
but it cannot be done in one go ,
because it 's very dangerous .
So , I skipped school last year and have been here ever since .
You 're so young , yet so brave !
Big Sister , once you can see again , I 'll take you out to play .
The world is a truly beautiful place .
Wong Kar Mun , when I remove the bandages on your eyes ,
it might hurt a little .
If it hurts too much , let me know .
We can always remove the bandages tomorrow .
Okay , give it a try ,
open your eyes slowly .
Mun , don 't force yourself if it hurts .
It hurts !
Is it too much ?
Dr. Lo , she must be in a lot of pain !
She 's never cried out in pain since she was a kid !
Easy , Granny , Dr. Lo knows what to do .
Please don 't worry yourself .
In fact , very few patients see immediate success .
It takes time for the eye and brain to work together .
Here .
Ying Ying .
Ying Ying !
Big Sister , can you see now ?
I 'm Ying Ying .
Can you really see me ?
It seems I can see now .
Fantastic ! Big Sister can see !
Nurse , Big Sister can see !
Nurse , Big Sister 's eyes are able to see now !
She sees me ! Come quickly ...
Granny ! The hospital called , Mun can see again !
What ?
Mun can see !
- Really ? - Go get changed , let 's go see her now .
Are you going to discharge me now ?
Not so soon .
Every cornea recipient starts off shortsighted ,
by as much as 1,000 degrees .
Only when your shortsightedness falls to about 200 degrees ,
will your eye muscles be able to adapt .
When will she have perfect eyesight then ?
No one has perfect eyesight ,
most people are shortsighted by about 100 degrees .
That sounds troublesome .
Will she need glasses ?
No need , madam .
All she needs is a pair of sunglasses for the time being .
Mun , get some rest .
If everything goes well , you can leave earlier .
You can take off your sunglasses now . Try to get used to the light gradually .
If you feel pain , or if your eyes start tearing up ,
that means you should close your eyes and let your eyes rest .
Here , I 'll help you onto the bed .
Nurse .
Is there a mirror in every washroom ?
I 'll take you there .
Here .
Slowly .
Take your time , call me if you need anything .
Who 's that ?
Ying Ying , is that you ?
Why are you so quiet ?
Big Sister , I 'm having another operation tomorrow .
You made a promise to take me out once I can see again .
So , hurry up with your operation , then we can go out and have fun .
Did they say you can leave now ?
Not yet .
But even when I do , I can always drop by to visit you .
Sis , let 's take a picture together .
- Let 's do it outside ! - Okay !
- Let 's go ... - Go where ?
Here , let 's take a picture here !
What 's this ?
- A camera . - A camera ?
Yes . Now , look this way .
Okay .
Ready ? One , two , three !
Madam , are you all right ?
Madam ...
I 'm freezing ...
Send this one to Block C.
We have a full house in the Block B Morgue .
Nurse ?
Is the old lady dead ?
It has been taken care of .
But last night ... I saw someone drop by to visit her .
They even went out together .
Are you sure ? We don 't allow any visitors here at night .
Where 's Ying Ying ?
She went in for an operation this morning .
Dr. Lo wanted you to stay for two more days for observation ,
but I 'll be away on flight duty for two weeks .
No one will be able to pick you up then .
It 's easier to have you discharged now .
This way , you and Granny can spend more time together .
My ! It 's already 3 : 00 p.m. !
I wonder if this place is easy to find .
Should have waited until I 'd returned . It 's only a few more days after all .
After meeting the therapist , I 'll put you in a taxi .
Granny will meet you downstairs .
Wonder if we can still make it ...
Our appointment was at 3 : 00 p.m. , we 're only ten minutes late .
I have to leave for work soon .
Excuse me , you 've mistaken my words .
Dr. Lo saw that you hadn 't arrived , so he went out to buy something .
Okay .
Dr. Lo 's back .
Where 's my three o 'clock ?
That 's her .
Mun , let 's go .
Let me introduce you to the nature of my work .
Starting from now ,
I am Miss Wong Kar Mun 's psychotherapist .
Since Miss Wong lost her sight at the age of two ,
her visual vocabulary is extremely limited ,
and she has probably forgotten most of even that .
For example ,
Miss Wong , please remove your glasses and let your eyes get used to the light .
Can you tell what 's in my hand ?
You 'll recognize it 's a stapler once you touch it ,
because all your previous knowledge of objects
was based on touch , not on sight .
Yet , you are no longer blind .
My job is to help you re-establish
how to use your eyes and understand what you see .
Actually , I 'm not too worried about that aspect .
What concerns me is the patient 's psychological state .
After regaining their sight , many patients end up feeling alienated and fearful .
Dr. Lo , is the other Dr. Lo a relative of yours ?
You mean my uncle ?
Yes , he 's my father 's younger brother .
So , what time do you finish work today ?
Miss Wong is my last patient for the day .
Well , you see , I need to catch my flight ,
so , can I trouble you to get Mun home after this ?
I see . Of course .
Besides , starting from today ,
I need to take Miss Wong outdoors for her training anyway .
Okay .
Sis , you can go ahead , I 'm fine by myself ,
I 'm used to it .
This is you as a little girl .
Your father shot this a long time ago , so that
you could look at it once your eyes healed .
It was seven or eight years ago .
He stopped filming ever since he divorced your mother .
Granny , is it true when Daddy comes back ,
he 'll take us to Vancouver ?
I know you don 't want to go ,
but Vancouver 's pace of life is slower ,
it 'll suit you better .
I can 't even read Chinese , how can I learn English ?
Granny , I don 't want to rely on others forever .
I want to learn to write and find a job in Hong Kong .
I want to be independent .
Your father might worry about you going to work .
I have to do the dishes , just take your time .
Hey , kid , what 's up ?
Sis , have you seen my report card ?
No , I haven 't .
Do you live upstairs ?
Mun , who 's that ?
It 's a little kid , Granny .
Did a report card ever fall into our balcony ?
That kid is poking fun at you . Just ignore him !
VIGIL
Kid , what are you munching on ?
I 'm very hungry .
What is it ? What 's your problem ?
Bravo !
We have two pieces of good news today , everyone .
First ...
Miss Tone Deaf had a successful operation !
And second , for our Christmas charity concert ,
we 'll have the honor to perform with Miss Vanessa-Mae !
Mr. Ching , why haven 't I received the practice schedule ?
Mun , you know , after all , we 're an organization for the blind .
You 're always welcome to come and practice , but perhaps ,
you should do something else for the performance ,
such as coordination , or taking care of our members .
I can even arrange for you to volunteer at the center .
Mr. Ching , I really want to take part in this performance .
I 've practiced so long for this concert .
I totally understand , however ...
Excuse me , Mr. Ching ,
Vanessa-Mae 's agent wants us to fax over our practice schedule .
I 'll be with you right away .
Mun , Mun ?
Let 's finish our discussion later .
I need to go now . See you .
- Granny ! - Are you leaving ?
Yes , to class .
Come back early for dinner . I 've prepared some special turnip soup .
Bye !
Sis , have you seen my report card ?
Report card ? Haven 't you found it yet ?
I really haven 't seen it .
Perhaps , you should ask someone else . Okay ?
Ying Ying !
Excuse me , I 'd like to talk to her .
Look what I 've got you .
Sis , I 've just gone through chemotherapy .
I 'm not supposed to eat . I 'll throw up if I do .
That 's all right , we 'll save it until you get better , okay ?
If only we had believed him just that once ,
or given him a chance to explain ...
he might still be here , playing video games .
Who would have expected him to jump off just like that ?
Suicide is a dreadful sin .
The souls of those who commit suicide
are obliged to repeat their painful deaths everyday .
To help him out of this vicious cycle of pain ,
we need to tackle the cause of his suicide .
Only then can his soul leave this world in peace .
Have you ever considered he might be telling the truth ?
Perhaps , he really did lose his report card .
Sir , have you been teaching here long ?
Yes , indeed . Many years .
This is calligraphy . I 'll teach you how to write .
Here , hold the brush and write .
Use your big thumb and index finger , form a circle just like this .
Like this ... and write . Here , try .
Very few want to learn calligraphy , nowadays .
I used to teach three lessons a week ,
now , I have only one lesson a week .
Now , try writing by yourself , okay ?
Practice on your own .
Why did you take my seat ?
What is this ? What is going on ?
What are you looking for ? Are you okay ?
How did this happen ?
Are you not feeling well ?
Is Dr. Lo here ?
Miss Wong , you were here two days ago .
Your next appointment isn 't till Friday .
He 's out for a meeting , he 'll be back at 5 : 00 p.m.
Will he definitely be here at 5 : 00 p.m. ?
Is it urgent ? I can page him if you want .
I 'll be back at 5 : 00 .
SANYANG CAFE
Can you see them , too ?
They usually don 't want you to notice them .
Give it some time , and you 'll get used to it .
All the stores nearby have been bought up ,
only my boss refuses to sell .
He seems to be expecting his wife and child to visit .
Actually , he can 't see them at all .
There 's been a car accident over there ...
Don 't move him , he may have some fractured bones .
Mun !
My secretary said you were asking for me . What 's the matter ?
Will you help me ?
Sure , of course I will . Do your eyes hurt ?
- Will you believe me ? - Yes .
What is it ?
That black figure , he came to take the dead .
What black figure ?
When I was at the hospital ...
I saw a black figure .
He took an old lady with him .
The next morning , the old lady was dead .
My room keeps changing suddenly into a different room .
I even saw a person with the lower half of her body missing .
When they rushed over , it was like an electric shock ...
my whole body went numb ...
Calm down . Tell me slowly .
When I was little ...
Granny told me ...
I was not an ordinary child ...
God had given me some obstacles ,
so that I would grow up to be an extraordinary person .
Now , I finally understand what it means to be extraordinary .
An extraordinary person can see things other people can 't see ...
feel pain other people won 't feel .
Maybe , I was never meant to see this world .
I don 't want to be confined in my own world anymore ,
terrified in bed every night ...
then awakening to horrors every morning .
I just want to be an ordinary person .
Wah , can you help me ?
Yes , yes .
One of my psychology professors from the States
has just come to Hong Kong for a visit .
Let 's meet him tomorrow , maybe he can help you .
How can you help me without believing me ?
Sis , what 's going on ?
Excuse me , I have to go .
Call me if you need anything .
Goodbye .
Who 's that ?
A friend .
He asked Yee to take something to a friend in the States .
Yes , that 's right .
You are home early . Aren 't you supposed to be back next week ?
Well ... a co-worker switched her shift with mine ,
so , I 'm back early .
You go home first , it 's so smoky here . Go on !
14TH FLOOR , UNIT-C
Sis , have you seen my report card ?
Why keep asking me ? I already told you I haven 't !
15TH FLOOR , UNIT-C
Uncle , listen to me ...
No way !
Only you can help us out !
I 've already said no !
If you still respect me as your uncle , and respect yourself as my nephew ,
you should have never approached me on this !
First of all , you should know only too well
what medical ethics are , regarding organ transplants .
And you should know better that
the identity of the cornea donor is concealed from me .
What black figures ?
One cornea transplant and she starts seeing ghosts ?
You actually believe that ?
What if I do ?
Then we have even less to talk about !
Uncle ...
Don 't tell me , you 're in love with your patient .
Hello ?
Wah , is this you ? Mun is in trouble !
Can you come over immediately ?
Yes , right away .
Yes , I admit , she 's more than a patient to me .
Mun ! Mun !
How long do you plan on hiding in this little room ?
Five years ? Seven ? Or 10 ?
You have to confront your problem sooner or later .
You want to play violin ? Go play with the group !
I can accept you pretending to be blind .
But even when you were blind , you didn 't just stay here .
I just want to help .
- Mun . - Mun !
Sister .
Ying Ying , what are you doing here ?
Sister , I can leave the hospital now .
You can leave ?
Yes , I don 't need any more operations , I can go to school now .
Then ...
Then once I am out of here ...
we can go out and play together ...
we can take pictures , we can even ...
I 'm so happy that you can see now ...
because this world is really beautiful .
Ying Ying ...
It 's all right ! Cheer up .
Stay strong and things will be all right .
Sis , I have to go now .
Ying Ying !
Wong Kar Mun , I want to tell you ...
Ying Ying has already ...
I know . I just saw her .
I know she 's dead .
YUEN KIT YING
What are you looking at ?
Ying Ying .
Can you see her ?
It wasn 't her .
Don 't know why she didn 't show up today .
Are you not afraid anymore ?
I don 't think I have a choice .
I have to see all these things anyway .
At least , I get to see the ones I care about .
SIS MUN
What 's this ?
Ying Ying made this for you .
What 's it say ?
" Don 't forget me . "
DON 'T FORGET ME
She put in the wrong photo , though .
Who 's this ?
That 's you ! You still don 't recognize yourself ?
What is going on ?
Who the hell are you ?
We believe that the last bit of consciousness of a mortal
carries over to the afterlife .
That is , the very thought of a person in their final moment ,
would become the eternal consciousness of their soul .
So , those who die a sudden death ,
would have no recollection of the instance of death .
Their souls remain in this world , as if they 're still alive .
But there are others who refuse to leave intentionally ,
mostly because of unsettled problems in their lifetime .
These souls can 't be consoled if their problems persist .
There is only one way to help them out ,
that is , to resolve what they left unresolved .
The woman Miss Wong keeps seeing after regaining her sight .
We have to resolve her problems so that she can move on .
I hope I haven 't done anything wrong .
Even if it 's wrong , it 'd be my fault , but I won 't regret it .
Were you reincarnated into the wrong body ?
Why are you so different from the rest of the family ?
Be careful .
BANGKOK , THAILAND
Dr. Lo believed you in the end ?
Let 's take it that Dr. Lo is not involved .
He 's a professional after all ...
- you know what I mean ? - Yes .
How much further ?
I 'm not sure .
It says here , that her Chinese name was Chiu Wai Ling ,
a Thai-born Chinese , I suppose .
Here are her hospital records .
This is Siam Rach Hospital , Siam Rach .
" Si-am-la ? "
Does " Si-am-la " mean " Siam " ?
Let 's get off to take a look .
SIAM RACH HOSPITAL
Hi .
Excuse me , is this hospital named Siam Rach Lunteban ?
- Yes . - Yes ?
I need to speak to a doctor here , his name is Eak .
Please come and take care of this .
Can I help you ?
Hi , I need to speak to a doctor in this hospital ,
his name is Eak .
Do you know him ?
No ?
But there is a doctor named Eak , right ?
It says here ,
this is the hospital , his name is Eak .
He 's not here now .
He 's not here now ?
Wah !
What is it ?
- This is the place . - What place ?
The place I 've been having nightmares about .
Nightmares ?
This has to be it !
- Doctor ! - What 's the matter ?
You have two visitors .
Mister , this is Dr. Eak .
- Are you Dr. Eak ? - Yes .
My name is Wah .
- Hi . - Nice to meet you .
It 's about her . She 's just had a cornea transplant .
So , we would like to thank the donor 's family .
We hope you can give us some details .
This is the information .
Are you two from Hong Kong ?
You speak Mandarin ?
Can you help us ?
Sorry , I can 't disclose our hospital records ,
not without the proper authorization .
Please understand .
Wait ! We need to see the donor 's family urgently ,
could you perhaps contact them , and see if they are willing to meet us ?
Her family will not be willing to meet with you .
Who are you to Ling ?
Please leave .
Wait !
After I got Ling 's corneas , I started to see things she used to see !
Ling was a sad girl ,
everyone in the village stayed away from her .
Why ?
From time to time , she would weep outside someone 's door ,
and afterwards ,
a person in that house would pass away .
So , everyone took her to be a devil and always chased her away on sight .
The children treated her like a monster .
I , too , threw stones at her when I was a kid ...
Because none of you could believe that she foresaw death ?
Maybe it was because of fear .
So , do you believe it now ?
This is it .
Mrs. Chui , these two friends are from Hong Kong .
Nobody welcomed Ling ...
so , she hardly ever set foot in the village .
Yet , on the night of the big fire ,
many saw her running around and shouting hysterically ,
as if talking to herself .
Since everyone detested Ling ,
no one paid any attention to her .
I only heard , some villagers threw water on her
to drive her away .
Around midnight , a big fire erupted
and kept burning till noon the next day .
Among the deceased , 300 were burned beyond recognition .
- How exactly did Ling die ? - She hanged herself .
Ling killed herself the day after the big fire .
Is Mrs. Chui all right ?
She 's fine .
So , you too believed that she wasn 't insane ,
that she only saw things no one else could .
She foresaw a big disaster and tried to warn everyone ,
but no one listened to her .
I don 't understand any of this spiritual stuff .
I just want you two to know that Ling was a very kind person ...
and she had a tough life .
Can I take a look at Ling 's room ?
Tonight ... I want to stay here .
I 'll take you to Ling 's grave tomorrow morning .
You 've been very kind to us , thank you .
You should go to bed now .
All right , I 'm staying next door , shout out if anything happens .
I know you 've wanted me to come here all this time .
Here I am now . What do you want to tell me ?
... ill-fated !
Hurry ! Take her to the hospital !
You are disaster !
Everything you speak is evil ! Shut up , for God 's sake !
You jinx ! It 's all because of you !
Told you not to come here !
She 's evil ! Don 't ever play with her !
Go save him ! Save my boy ...
Help him ... Make him breathe !
For God 's sake ...
She 's evil !
It 's all your fault !
Mrs. Chui , I know how to help Ling .
Let 's go upstairs to see her .
Her most painful time was not in the past , it 's right now !
Since she killed herself , she 's been trapped
in a time warp , constantly repeating her suicide .
She 's already dead , how can she die again ?
Mrs. Chui , listen to me .
Your daughter will appear upstairs very soon .
Let 's go up to see her !
I won 't see her !
I spent my whole life protecting her ,
I never once gave up on her ,
but she gave up on herself !
For that , I can never forgive her !
Just listen , I 'm sure you hear this sound every night .
Ling died at 3 : 00 , didn 't she ?
Mrs. Chui , come with me and you 'll understand .
I 'm not going anywhere !
Mama ...
Help me ...
Ling ?
Help me !
Help me ...
Is it Ling ?
Is it really Ling ?
Mama ...
Help me ...
Ling , you were the one who left me ...
You were the one who left me ...
Mama , help me !
Ling , Mama 's coming !
Ling ! Ling !
Daughter , Ma 's right here .
Don 't be afraid ...
no one can bully you anymore .
Mama , I 'm so sorry ,
I was wrong ...
please forgive me !
I 've already forgiven you .
Mun !
What happened ?
Are you all right ?
IN LOVING MEMORY OF BELOVED DAUGHTER CHIU WAI LING
MAE CHAEM
Hurry ! Pull him out !
Careful ! Come on , keep pulling !
Over there ! Move !
Run for your life !
Go , go !
Something 's happening , get out , quick !
Granny , leave your house now !
Leave your house now !
Brother , run for your life !
Run quickly ! Run !
Please come out now ! Run !
Please come out now ! Run ...
Pack and run ! A disaster is coming !
Run now !
What 's she saying ?
Run ! Get out !
To your left . Move over !
Move over !
Mun !
Go ! Move over !
Run now !
Mun ...
Ling disappeared ever since that day .
I hold no resentment towards her ,
as I saw and experienced the same pain that she did .
But I 've seen more .
I 've seen pain , but I 've also seen beauty .
Never again will I ask why am I blind
for I 've seen the most beautiful things in this world ,
things I 'll never forget .